Finding Aid for William G. Milliken papers 1961-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Regional Offices, 48 linear feet
  - Detroit 1969-1982
    - 1969-1975
      - Administrative
        - Departments/Commissions
          - Housing and Urban Development
            - Miscellaneous (Box 901)
          - Public Health (Box 901)
          - Social Services
            - Aid for Dependent Children (Box 901)
            - Delinquent Youth (Box 901)
            - Suspended Social Workers (Box 901)
        - Press (WGM Speeches) 1969-1971, 2 folders (Box 901)
      - Civil Rights Commission
        - Memberships Lists 1968-1972 (Box 901)
        - Administrative
          - Audit Conferences (Box 901)
          - Budget 1968-1975, 4 folders (Box 901)
        - Complaints
          - Summary of Complaints 1970-1972 (Box 902)
          - Cases Heard 1970 (Box 902)
          - Air Engineering Corporation 1973 (Box 902)
          - Kennedy, Sharon (Box 902)
          - Real Estate Appraisals/Acquisitions I-496 Corridor (Lansing) (Box 902)
          - Age (Box 902)
          - Employment, 3 folders (Box 902)
          - Law Enforcement (Box 902)
          - Public Accommodations (Box 902)
          - Sex Discrimination (Box 902)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 902)
        - Correspondence/Memos 1969-1974, 2 folders (Box 902)
        - Divisions: Community Service, 3 folders (Box 902)
        - Divisions: Compliance, 2 folders (Box 902)
        - Meetings
          - Presentation to Milliken March 1972 (Box 903)
          - Special Executive Session September 1970 (Box 903)
          - February 1971-January 1973, 18 folders (Box 903)
        - Press Releases 1968-1971, 2 folders (Box 903)
        - Reports
          - A Plan to Improve the Complaints and Investigation Process 1972, 4 folders (Box 903)
          - Staff Weekly 1969-1970 (Box 904)
          - Commissioner Friday 1969-1972, 14 folders (Box 904)
          - Monthly 1973-1974 (Box 904)
          - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 904)
          - Michigan State Classified Service 1971 (Box 905)
        - Special Projects
          - Busing (Box 905)
          - Detroit Plan (Box 905)
          - Migrant Farm Labor 1969 (Box 905)
          - School Disorder (Box 905)
          - School Employment and Enrollment 1973 (Box 905)
          - Statewide Leadership Conference (Box 905)
          - Stress Program (Box 905)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Civil Rights/Civil Service Issues 1969 (Box 905)
          - Don Haney's TV Program June 1970 (Box 905)
          - Proposed Michigan Civil Rights Act 1973 (Box 905)
      - Local Government, Special Commission on
        - General (Box 905)
        - Report 1972 (Box 905)
        - Fiscal Powers/Functions (Box 905)
        - Subcommittee on Regionalism, 2 folders (Box 905)
      - Migrants
        - General 1970 (Box 905)
        - Commission on Agricultural Labor 1969-1970 (Box 905)
        - Governor's Speech on Migrants (Box 905)
        - Governor's Task Force on Migrant Labor (Box 905)
        - Housing, 2 folders (Box 905)
        - Migrant Services Report 1973 (Box 905)
        - Rural Manpower Center (MSU) (Box 905)
        - United Migrants for Opportunity (Box 905)
      - Ombudsman
        - Complaints-arranged by client's name
          - Summary Index (Box 906)
          - A-I (Box 906)
          - J-Sn (Box 907)
          - So-Z (Box 908)
        - Complaints-chronological
          - June 1972-1974, 4 folders (Box 908)
        - Correspondence/Memos (Carole Cromwell) 1973-1975, 2 folders (Box 908)
      - Regionalism
        - The Option Process (TOP) 1972-1973
          - Conference 1972, 2 folders (Box 909)
          - Task Force 1972-1973, 3 folders (Box 909)
        - Commissions and Committees
          - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 909)
          - Governor's Subcommittee (Box 909)
          - Regional Citizens' Organization (Box 909)
          - Swallow Subcommittee (Box 909)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Media (Box 909)
          - Rationale for Reorganization (Box 909)
          - State Planning Model and Goals (Box 909)
          - Urban Needs Analysis (Box 909)
        - Spanish-Speaking Population in Michigan
          - General, 3 folders (Box 909)
          - Spanish-American Community (Box 909)
          - Spanish-Speaking Commission (Box 909)
          - Spanish-Speaking Funds List (Box 909)
          - Tutorial Programs (Box 909)
      - Roy Williams
        - Correspondence 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 910)
        - Center for Resources on Institutional Oppression 1974 (Box 910)
        - Ex-Offenders (Box 910)
        - Executive Office Projects 1974 (Box 910)
        - Inner-City Business Improvement Forum 1974 (Box 910)
        - International Association of Governmental Labor Officials 1974 (Box 910)
        - Labor 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 910)
        - Manpower 1975 (Box 910)
        - Minority Business Enterprise 1974 (Box 910)
        - National Urban Coalition (Box 910)
        - Neighborhood Education Authority 1974 (Box 910)
        - Papers
          - "Rethinking Race and Group Relations" (Box 910)
          - "Social Conflict and Political Estrangement, 1958-1972" (Box 910)
      - Topical Files
        - Action Grants Summary List (Box 910)
        - Affirmative Action (Box 910)
        - Benton Harbor School District, 8 folders (Box 910)
        - Blacks, 4 folders (Box 910)
        - Campership Program (Box 910)
        - Children/Youth, 6 folders (Box 910)
        - Children/Youth: White House Conference on Children, 6 folders (Box 911)
        - Civil Service (Box 911)
        - Community Action Program (Box 911)
        - Crime, 5 folders (Box 911)
        - Detroit
          - Charter Revision Committee August 1973 (Box 911)
          - Critical Area Analysis 1969 (Box 911)
          - Police Department (Box 911)
          - Population (Box 911)
          - Renaissance Foundation 1971 (Box 911)
        - Drug Abuse/Alcoholism, 8 folders (Box 911)
        - Education, 6 folders (Box 912)
        - Education: Higher, 5 folders (Box 912)
        - Equal Employment Opportunity Action Plan 1974 (Box 912)
        - Ex-Offenders (Box 912)
        - Ford Foundation for Michigan (Box 912)
        - Franklin-Wright Nail Driving Ceremony 1974 (Box 912)
        - Group Homes (Box 912)
        - Halfway Homes (Box 912)
        - Health Care Facilities (Box 912)
        - Health Maintenance Organizations (Box 912)
        - Homesteading (Box 912)
        - Housing, 8 folders (Box 912)
        - Human Resources Services Center (Box 913)
        - Hunger Task Force (Box 913)
        - Indians (Box 913)
        - Integrated Grant Administration Program 1972 (Box 913)
        - Juvenile Delinquents (Box 913)
        - Juvenile Services System (Box 913)
        - Macomb County Community College Project (Box 913)
        - Manistee Music Camp (Box 913)
        - Minority Business (Box 913)
        - Moving Detroit Forward 1975 (Box 913)
        - Music Enrichment Proposal (Box 913)
        - New Bethel Report (Homicide) (Box 913)
        - New Detroit, 7 folders (Box 913)
        - Nursing Homes (Box 913)
        - Nutrition (Box 913)
        - Oakdale Cooperative Homes (Box 913)
        - Operation Understanding Grant (Box 913)
        - Peace Corps (Box 913)
        - Planning Coordination, Office of (Box 913)
        - Preschool Profile: Detroit, Highland Park, and Hamtramck 1971 (Box 913)
        - Primary Results (Box 913)
        - Prisons (Box 913)
        - Public Health (Box 913)
        - Regional Development Corporation (Box 913)
        - Reorganization (Box 913)
        - Retiree Affairs (Box 913)
        - Revenue Sharing (State) (Box 913)
        - Runaways (Box 913)
        - Sacred Heart Seminary (Box 914)
        - Senior Citizens, 6 folders (Box 914)
        - Social Security Amendment (Box 914)
        - Social Services (Box 914)
        - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments 1969-1975, 7 folders (Box 914)
        - Stadium Project: Detroit, 4 folders (Box 914)
        - State Office Building (Detroit) (Box 915)
        - Substate District Study (Box 915)
        - Taxes (Box 915)
        - Think Tank (Box 915)
        - Transportation (Box 915)
        - Unemployment Compensation (Box 915)
        - Urban Affairs Council, 8 folders (Box 915)
        - Urban Needs (Box 915)
        - Urban Reclamation (Box 915)
        - Welfare (Box 915)
        - Women's Drug Collective (Box 915)
        - Miscellaneous, 8 folders (Box 915)
    - 1976-1982
      - Mental Health
        - Administration
          - Audits (Box 916)
          - Budget, 3 folders (Box 916)
          - Director Search Committee, 3 folders (Box 916)
          - Emergency Rule (Box 916)
          - Federal Funds (Box 916)
          - Federal Needs (Box 916)
          - Goals (Box 916)
          - Guidelines (Box 916)
          - Planning (Box 916)
          - Progress Reports (Box 916)
          - Staff Meetings (Box 916)
          - Transfer Issue (Box 916)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 916)
        - Correspondence/Memoranda
          - Janet Coyle (Box 916)
          - Jim Jordan (Box 916)
          - Bill Long (Box 916)
          - Frank Ochberg (Box 916)
          - Stan Pratt (Box 916)
          - Mary Rave (Box 916)
          - V. A. Stehman (Box 916)
        - Topical Files
          - Abuse in Mental Health Institutions
            - Bishop Panel, 2 folders (Box 917)
            - Joint Legislative Committee, 3 folders (Box 917)
          - Adult Foster Care (Box 917)
          - Alternative Intermediate Services (Box 917)
          - Children's Inpatient Units (Box 917)
          - Children's Services (Box 917)
          - Clinton Valley Center (Box 917)
          - Coldwater Regional Center (Box 917)
          - Community Mental Health Boards (Box 917)
          - Community Placement, 5 folders (Box 917)
          - Current Mental Health Issues (Box 917)
          - Deinstitutionalization of Mentally Ill (Box 917)
          - Detroit-Wayne County Community Mental Health Board, 2 folders (Box 917)
          - Developmental Disability Council, 2 folders (Box 918)
          - Hawthorn Center (Box 918)
          - Hospital Accreditation (Box 918)
          - House Committee on Mental Health (Box 918)
          - Human Services Cabinet (Box 918)
          - Inter-Agency Agreements (Box 918)
          - Investigations (Box 918)
          - Involuntary Commitment Task Force (Box 918)
          - Joint Oversight Committee (Box 918)
          - Kalamazoo Regional Psychiatric Hospital (Box 918)
          - Legislation, 3 folders (Box 918)
          - Litigation, 3 folders (Box 918)
          - Mental Health Advisory Council (Box 918)
          - Mental Health Museum (Box 918)
          - Metropolitan Regional Office (Box 918)
          - Michigan Association of Retarded Citizens (Box 918)
          - Michigan Association of Community Mental Health Boards (Box 918)
          - Michigan Depression Project (Box 918)
          - Michigan Mental Health Association (Box 918)
          - Michigan Mental Health /code (Box 918)
          - Michigan State Plan for Developmental Disabilities, 2 folders (Box 918)
          - Northville Regional Psychiatric Hospital (Box 919)
          - Northville Regional Training Center (Box 919)
          - Nursing Care Benchmark (Box 919)
          - Nursing Homes (Box 919)
          - Oakdale Regional Center for Developmental Disabilities, 2 folders (Box 919)
          - Plymouth Center for Human Development, 6 folders (Box 919)
          - Protective/Advisory Services for Disabled Citizens, 3 folders (Box 919)
          - Recipient Rights
            - Evaluation Project, 5 folders (Box 920)
            - Office, 5 folders (Box 920)
            - Task Force (Box 920)
          - Retarded Citizens, Northwest Association for (Box 920)
          - State of the State (Mental Health) (Box 920)
          - Unification of the Public Mental Health System Committee, 3 folders (Box 920)
          - Walter Reuther Facility (Box 920)
          - Wayne County, 3 folders (Box 920)
          - Ypsilanti State Hospital (Box 920)
      - Refugees
        - Immigrant Groups: Indochinese Relief
          - Private Groups, 4 folders (Box 921)
          - State of Michigan, 3 folders (Box 921)
          - United States Departments, 2 folders (Box 921)
        - Immigrant Groups: Cubans (Box 921)
        - Michigan Programs (Office of Refugee Resettlement) (Box 921)
        - Miscellaneous Programs (Box 921)
        - Correspondence (Box 921)
        - Legislation 1979, 3 folders (Box 921)
        - Geneva Conference (Box 921)
        - Visit of West Germans to Grand Rapids 1979 (Box 921)
      - Title XX
        - Wayne County Planning Committee
          - Minutes/Reports 1976-1977 (Box 922)
          - Agenda 1971-1978 (Box 922)
          - Correspondence 1970-1978 (Box 922)
          - Membership Lists 1976-1977 (Box 922)
          - Financial Data 1973-1979, 4 folders (Box 922)
          - Needs Assessment Subcommittee 1976-1977 (Box 922)
          - Subplanning Component 1976-1978 (Box 922)
        - Wayne County Advisory Committee
          - Minutes 1977-1981 (Box 922)
          - Correspondence 1976-1981 (Box 922)
          - Agenda 1977-1980 (Box 922)
          - Membership Lists 1978 (Box 922)
          - Forum Committee, 2 folders (Box 922)
          - Purchase of Service Subcommittee (Box 922)
        - Michigan
          - Organizational Charts 1975, 1979 (Box 922)
          - Advisory Committee 1975-1980, 2 folders (Box 922)
          - Head Start Training 1974-1975 (Box 922)
      - Roy Williams
        - Correspondence
          - Charles Brown: Ombudsman, 4 folders (Box 923)
          - Carol Carrington 1980, 2 folders (Box 923)
          - Jean Hammond 1980 (Box 923)
          - William Jones (Box 923)
          - Jim Jordan 1979-1980, 6 folders (Box 923)
          - Tahira Khalid 1980 (Box 923)
          - Laura Litfin 1980 (Box 923)
          - Al Ward 1979-1980, 3 folders (Box 924)
          - Roy L. Williams 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Holly Witkowski 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 924)
        - Executive Office Staff
          - Governor Milliken 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Patrick Babcock 1981-1982 (Box 924)
          - Jan Bocskay 1979-1981 (Box 924)
          - James Brickley 1978-1980 (Box 924)
          - Barbara Debrdodt 1980 (Box 924)
          - John Dempsey 1974-1981, 7 folders (Box 924)
          - Nancy Docter 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Glenn Friedly 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Billie Harrison 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Bill Long 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Mark McKelvey 1980 (Box 924)
          - Stan Pratt 1980 (Box 924)
          - Ron Quincy 1979 (Box 924)
          - Richard Schlaff 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Doug Smith 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - George Weeks 1982 (Box 924)
          - Press Section 1979-1980 (Box 924)
          - Miscellaneous 1977-1980, 2 folders (Box 924)
        - Topical Files
          - Accounting Aid Society (Box 925)
          - African Trade Conference 1982 (Box 925)
          - Aging, City of Detroit, 2 folders (Box 925)
          - American Development Corporation (Box 925)
          - American Indian Services (Box 925)
          - Anti-Inflation Conference (Box 925)
          - Arab-Americans, 2 folders (Box 925)
          - Associated Food Dealers (Box 925)
          - Benton Harbor (Box 925)
          - Black Applied Resources Center (Box 925)
          - Black Awareness in Television (Box 925)
          - Black Caucus (Michigan Democratic) (Box 925)
          - Black Social Workers (Box 925)
          - Black United Fund (Box 925)
          - Blacks
            - Baptist Ministers (Box 925)
            - Capitalism (Box 925)
            - Civic Leaders (Box 925)
            - Communicators (Box 925)
            - Democratic Party (Box 925)
            - Economic Development Report (Box 925)
            - History Publications (Box 925)
            - Suppliers Market (Box 925)
            - Television/Radio (Box 925)
            - Women (Box 925)
          - BOLD (Beginning Opportunities for Leadership Development) (Box 925)
          - Booker T. Washington Business Association (Box 925)
          - Boundary Change Committee (Box 925)
          - Budget
            - City/State (Box 925)
            - Michigan 1975-1982, 4 folders (Box 925)
          - Busing, 4 folders (Box 926)
          - Cadillac Center Project (Box 926)
          - Census 1980 (Box 926)
          - Child Abuse, 2 folders (Box 926)
          - Christmas Reception (Box 926)
          - Chrysler Corporation (Box 926)
          - "Cities In Trouble" 1976 (Box 926)
          - Citizens for Better Care (Box 926)
          - Civil Service (Box 926)
          - Commerce, 2 folders (Box 926)
          - Community Affairs, 2 folders (Box 926)
          - Community Development Act (Box 926)
          - Community Development and Assistance (Box 926)
          - Community Development Cabinet, 4 folders (Box 926)
          - Community Development Program (Box 926)
          - Community Placement (Box 926)
          - Community Profiles (Box 926)
          - Complaints (Box 927)
          - Comprehensive Education and Training Act (Box 927)
          - Concerned Citizens Council (Box 927)
          - Conferences (Box 927)
          - Continental Africa Chamber of Commerce (Box 927)
          - Conventions (Box 927)
          - Corrections, 4 folders (Box 927)
          - Crime Roundtable (Box 927)
          - Crime Task Force (Box 927)
          - Detroit
            - Budget (Box 927)
            - Business for Detroit Seminar (Box 927)
            - City Council (Box 927)
            - Detroit Development Corp., 3 folders (Box 927)
            - Detroit Economic Growth, 2 folders (Box 927)
            - Detroit General Hospital (Box 927)
            - Economic Development Plan (Box 927)
            - Finances (Box 927)
            - Housing, 2 folders (Box 928)
            - Mayor's Office (Box 928)
            - Port Authority (Box 928)
            - Public Schools (Box 928)
            - Renaissance, 2 folders (Box 928)
            - Riverfront, 2 folders (Box 928)
            - State of the City (Box 928)
            - Utility Tax (Box 928)
          - Disabled Persons (Box 928)
          - Economic Development-Michigan, 2 folders (Box 928)
          - Education, 3 folders (Box 928)
          - Energy (Box 929)
          - Enterprise Zones (Box 929)
          - Epilepsy Center of Michigan (Box 929)
          - Family, White House Conference on the (Box 929)
          - Farm-a-lot (Box 929)
          - Frozen Dessert Task Force (Box 929)
          - Future Problem Solving Bowl 1980 (Box 929)
          - General Motors (Poletown Plant) (Box 929)
          - Grants and Transfers (Box 929)
          - Great Lakes Maritime Academy (Box 929)
          - Hamtramck (Box 929)
          - Halsey, Donald (Box 929)
          - Health, 2 folders (Box 929)
          - Henderson, Erma (Box 929)
          - Highland Park, 2 folders (Box 929)
          - Highways (M-275) (Box 929)
          - Hines Park Problem (Box 929)
          - Housing, 6 folders (Box 929)
          - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 929)
          - Khalid, Tahira (Box 929)
          - Koinonia Medical Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 929)
          - Labor, 3 folders (Box 930)
          - Lafayette Clinic (Box 930)
          - Lafayette Park Steering Committee (Box 930)
          - Legal Aid Defenders of Detroit (Box 930)
          - Legislation Proposed (Box 930)
          - Management and Budget (Box 930)
          - Maritime Project (Box 930)
          - Medicaid (Box 930)
          - Metropolitan Youth Foundation (Box 930)
          - Michigan Chronicle (Box 930)
          - Mid-America Regional Commission (Box 930)
          - Minority Business, 2 folders (Box 930)
          - Minority Economic Development Committee (Box 930)
          - NAACP (Box 930)
          - NGA (Box 930)
          - NGA Conference in Detroit 1977, 7 folders (Box 930)
          - National Urban League (Box 931)
          - Neighborhood Service Organization, 3 folders (Box 931)
          - New Detroit, Inc.
            - General, 7 folders (Box 931)
            - Education Commission (Box 931)
            - Minority Economic Development (Box 931)
            - Project Advisory Committee (Box 931)
            - Property Tax Work Group (Box 931)
          - Nigerian Trade (Box 931)
          - North American Indian Association (Box 931)
          - North End Concerned Citizens (Box 931)
          - Operation FAST (Box 931)
          - Opportunities Industrialization Centers, 3 folders (Box 931)
          - Palmer Park Center for the Arts (Box 932)
          - Parke-Davis Company (Box 932)
          - Plymouth Center for Human Development (Box 932)
          - Pontiac (Box 932)
          - Pontiac Silverdome (Box 932)
          - Public Health (Detroit) (Box 932)
          - Rail Vehicle Assembly in Michigan (Box 932)
          - Recipient Rights, Office of (Box 932)
          - Recreational Planning (Box 932)
          - Redlining (Box 932)
          - Research/Consultants (Box 932)
          - Revenue and Expense Reduction 1981 (Box 932)
          - Revenue Sharing (Box 932)
          - Rockwood Prison Proposal (Box 932)
          - Royal Oak Township (Box 932)
          - Satellite TV Corporation (Box 932)
          - School Violence (Box 932)
          - Senior Citizens (Box 932)
          - Set Aside Legislation (Box 932)
          - Sexual Harassment (Box 932)
          - Simmons, Richard (Deputy Mayor, Detroit) (Box 932)
          - Social Services, 5 folders (Box 932)
          - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments
            - A-E, 7 folders (Box 932)
            - F-W, 10 folders (Box 933)
          - Southeast Michigan Transportation Authority (Box 933)
          - Southwest Detroit Development Project, 2 folders (Box 933)
          - State Government Reorganization (Box 933)
          - State of the State (Box 933)
          - Street Chariot (Box 933)
          - Summer Youth Programs (Box 934)
          - Trade (Japanese) (Box 934)
          - Transportation, 2 folders (Box 934)
          - Unions (Detroit) (Box 934)
          - United Community Services 1978-1982, 5 folders (Box 934)
          - United Negro College Fund (Box 934)
          - Urban Affairs, 3 folders (Box 934)
          - Urban Coordinating Council (Box 935)
          - Urban Stress, 2 folders (Box 935)
          - Utilities and Energy, Michigan Coalition (Box 935)
          - Vehicle Inspection/Maintenance (Box 935)
          - Veterans (Box 935)
          - Ward, Albert M (Box 935)
          - Washington Office (Box 935)
          - Water Quality Management (Box 935)
          - Wayne County, 10 folders (Box 935)
          - Wayne State University (Box 935)
          - Welfare Reform (Box 935)
          - Wild, J. (Polk County Attorney's Office) (Box 935)
          - Women in Transition (Box 935)
          - Womens' Commission (Box 935)
          - Young, Dr. Claud (Box 935)
          - Young, Mayor Coleman, 2 folders (Box 935)
          - Youth, 9 folders (Box 935)
  - Upper Peninsula 1974-1982